{
    "id": "1f0c14fc1e664533a414c49627c43e34",
    "title": "So, very and too",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "15dc3d29a8134a8fb2a26599b49e641d",
            "title": "So, Very, and Too | Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "It was ………………. dark that I could not see anything.",
                    "description": "'So' shows the effect or result. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "very",
                        "too"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The tea is ………………… hot for me to drink.",
                    "description": "Note the pattern 'too...to'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "too",
                        "so",
                        "very"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I was …………………. busy to meet them.",
                    "description": "Note the pattern 'too...to'. We use 'too' to indicate undesirable extremes. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "too",
                        "very"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The evening was ………………. cold.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "very",
                        "too",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "There are far ……………….. many mistakes in the essay.",
                    "description": "Far can modify 'too many', but it cannot modify 'very many'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "very",
                        "too",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He behaved ……………….. rudely that we wanted to slap him.",
                    "description": "Note the pattern 'so...that'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "very",
                        "so",
                        "too"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am ……………….. happy today.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "very",
                        "too",
                        "Either so or very"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………….. many people agree with me.",
                    "description": "In some situations both 'so' and very' are possible with similar meanings. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "So",
                        "Very",
                        "Too",
                        "Either so or very"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "The coat was ……………….. expensive that I didn’t buy it.",
                    "description": "Note the pattern 'so...that'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "too",
                        "so",
                        "very"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is .................................... frail to walk without support.",
                    "description": "Note the pattern 'too...to'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "too",
                        "very"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}